

678 My Road, Los Angeles, CA 21098 c.marsden@myemail.com (123) 456-7890 Driven and creative retail makeup artist with 1+ years of experience demonstrating and selling luxury makeup in a large department store setting. Skilled at building a warm rapport with clients and using active Listening skills to assess their needs and preferences. Talented at demonstrating and explaining the advantages of products and educating clients on howto recreate looks at home.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **RETAIL MAKEUP ARTIST**

Charlotte Tilbury. Los Angeles, CA I July 2019 - Present

- Demonstrate and explain products and benefits to customers and provide skin tone matching services, approximate
  10 customers per day
- ♦ Listen to customers' requirements to create Looks and educate them on makeup application
- Meet demanding personal sales targets, increasing 5% per quarter, and work collaboratively with colleagues to achieve team goals
- Maintain a tidy, inviting, and hygienic work area and create attractive visual merchandising displays of new product lines
- Advise customers on skincare routines according to skin type

#### **RETAIL ASSISTANT**

Sephora, Los Angeles. CA I February 2016 - July 2019

- Greeted guests cordially and handled customer inquiries efficiently and courteously in person and over the phone
- Processed cash and card payments, returns, and refunds using the point-of-sale system
- ♦ Maintained an attractive and hazard-free store environment
- Kept an updated knowledge of industry trends and new product Lines and explained product details to customers

## **EDUCATION**

ASSOCIATE OF SCIENCE IN COSMETOLOGY

El Camino College, Torrance, CA I September 2017-June 2019

## **KEY SKILLS**

- Strong salesperson
- · Skilled at skin tone matching
- Detailed knowledge of airbrush makeup application techniques
- Works quickly and consistently under time pressure
- Creative and adept at creating looks to meet a brief

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

 Cosmetology License, California State Board of Cosmetology and Barbers, 2019